Now in this lecture, I'm going to show you a hands-on demo of the Amazon Bedrock prompt caching.
So what I have done is I have just written a Lambda function demo prompt caching.
And if you can just show you the code here, so what I have done is I have created some static
prefix or system prompt. And it just generic information that helps the foundation model
to get some context. So this is going to be reusable or cacheable. And then I said,
okay, cache point as type default. And then I have some dynamic user prompt. Again,
I put a lot of it as static. Now the only thing that is going to change here is the machine ID.
So as I change the value of the machine ID, I will ask it to summarize. So then we'll see
what is the reduction in the number of tokens. So basically, since this is static, we should see
some reduction in the number of tokens and also latency. Okay, so that's basically the function
I have written. Okay, now let's take a look. So I've already written a prompt caching test.
So let me just quickly show you. So you can see here, this is the machine ID. And right now,
it is 4, 5, 2, 2. So I will run it once. So it will store the static part of the prompt.
And then I will change the machine ID. And basically, it will change this machine ID.
But we'll still be able to reuse some part of the static prompt. Okay, now let me just go ahead
and invoke this, let me just go ahead and say test. Let me just click on this.
Okay, now you can see here, basically latency is 1, 3, 4, 5 milliseconds. And the number of
total tokens used is we have the input token 143 and output token is 350. So let me just
copy this and we'll see the change. So let me just paste it here. And now let me just go back to
my lambda function. Okay, now I'm just going to change the machine ID. So I'll just click on this.
And let's say the machine ID is 99. And then I'll just do a save. Okay, now this has been saved.
Now let me just go ahead and test it again. Okay, so it continues to run. Okay, I waited a few
seconds. And now it has generated a response. So you can see latency this time is 1, 0, 7, 4 seconds.
If we just go to the previous request, the latency was 1, 3, 4, 5. So it has reduced the latency.
So now we are also able to see this cache read input tokens. So it has reused 77 tokens.
Obviously this was a very short prompt that we had written. But if you're going to write
longer prompts and the documents are going to be much more large, there's going to be
lot of reusability. So I just wanted to quickly show you how you can use prompt caching.
Now you can also see this capability from the console itself. So if I just go to this chat
playground and let me just select a model, let me say no more probe. And if I just scroll down here,
you'll be able to see prompt caching. So I can enable this and your prompts and model responses
are automatically saved in cache checkpoint. But when you try it through the console sometimes it
doesn't work. So that's why I showed it to you programmatically. Okay, so that's pretty much it from
this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.